Rupinder Kaur

rupinderkaur9202@gmail.com +16049680213 Surrey, BC

Professional Summary

Highly motivated and customer oriented professional with 4+ years of experience in delivering exceptional software products. **Seeking a Software Engineer position** with your company to utilize my strong Java SpringBoot Programming, Hibernatem, OOPs & AWS skills.

(Linkedin.com: rupinder-kaur-5873b51b6, Leetcode: roopk)

Skills

Java 17, Java11, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Spring Security, Python, OAUTH, LDAP, JWT, REST, Micro Services, AWS, Kafka, Jenkins, CI/CD, Kubernetes, Yantra, Docker, PostgreSQL, Gradle, Maven, Intellij, Eclipse, JMeter, JUnit, Integration Testing, Windows & Linux

Experience

Software Engineer

Infosys (Telstra Australia) • India 12/2022 - 04/2023

I worked with Telstra (an Australian Telecommunications company) where I was responsible for creating piece of REST APIs which generated invoices.

- · Received recognition for assisting client on debugging time critical issues
- Utilized Skills: Java 17, SpringBoot 3.x, Spring Security, OAuth, LDAP, JWT, IntelliJ, gradle7, maven, JUnit, Jira, Confluence, Postman, Git/Github, Agile, bamboo, AWS, Kubernetes, yantra, Microservices, Docker, REST API, PostgreSQL

Software Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services (HSBC Canada & US Market) • India 10/2020 - 12/2022

I worked with HSBC where I was responsible for creating backend services for browser & mobile used to display banking transaction history & domestic transactions on browser and App. Also worked on handling different account types (Wealth & Private banking users) while designing APIs.

- Performed software testing, provided 24/7 support to clients, and developed plans for future software development
- Received recognition from HSBC Canada for excellent debugging skills
- Achieved excellent yearly performance ratings throughout my tenure
- Utilized skills: Java11, RX java, Spring Boot 2.x, Spring Security, OAUTH, LDAP, JWT, Restful Web Services, Spring tool suite, maven 3.x, JUnit, Jira, Confluence, Postman, Git, Agile, Jenkins, PCF, Anypoint, REST API, Microservices, AWS, Docker

Software Engineer

UST Global (Dell Technologies) • India 08/2018 - 10/2020

I worked for Dell Technologies where i was responsible for creating a backend service for different types of performance testing pipelines. These APIs were used to generate pipelines for all projects in Dell.

• Utilized Skills: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Restful Web Services, Hibernate 4.x, MySQL, Eclipse, Visual Studio code, maven, JUnit, Angular, Bootstrap, REST API, Maven, MongoDB

Education

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science)

Punjab Technical University • India 05/2015

- A four year professional degree with core Computer Science fundamental and advance subjects.
- Received full scholarship for the degree
- Excelled in multiple subjects such as Java Programming, Data structures, Object Oriented programming

Languages

English, Hindi, Punjabi

Certificates

250+ problems solved on LeetCode, Java Spring Boot Enterprise development (TCS)